In some of the earlier videos,
在以前的视频中，（字幕翻译：中国海洋大学，黄海广，haiguang2000@qq.com）
I was talking about PCA as
我谈论PCA
a compression algorithm where you
作为压缩算法。
may have say, a thousand dimensional
在那里你可能需要把1000维
data and compress it
的数据压缩
to a hundred dimensional feature back
一百维特征，
there, or have three dimensional
或具有三维
data and compress it to a two dimensional representation.
数据压缩到一二维表示。
So, if this is a
所以，如果这是一个
compression algorithm, there should
压缩算法，应该
be a way to go back from
能回到
this compressed representation, back to
这个压缩表示，回
an approximation of your original high dimensional data.
到你原有的高维数据的一种近似。
So, given z(i), which maybe
所以，给定的Z（i），这可能
a hundred dimensional, how do
一百维，怎么办
you go back to your original
你回到你原来的
representation x(i), which was maybe a thousand dimensional?
表示x（i），这可能是一千维的数组？
In this video, I'd like to
这个视频，我想
describe how to do that.
描述如何去做。
In the PCA algorithm, we may have an example like this.
在PCA算法，我们可能有一个这样的样本。
So maybe that's my example x1
也许那是那是我们的样本x1，
and maybe that's my example x2.
也许那是我的样本X2。
And what we do
我们做的是，
is, we take these examples and
我们把这些样本
we project them onto this one dimensional surface.
投射到这一个维平面。
And then now we need
然后现在我们需要
to use only a real number,
只使用一个实数，
say z1, to specify the
比如Z1，指定
location of these points after
这些点的位置后
they've been projected onto this one dimensional surface. So
他们被投射到这一个三维曲面。所以
, given a point
，给定一个点
like this, given a point z1,
这样，给定一个点Z1，
how can we go back to
我们怎么能回去
this original two-dimensional space?
这个原始的二维空间？
And in particular, given the
特别是，给定
point z, which is an
Z点，这是一个
r, can we map
R，我们可以映射
this back to some approximate
这些来回到一些近似
representation x and r2
表示X和R2
of whatever the original value of the data was?
的任何数据的原始值？
So, whereas z equals U
而z等于
reduced transverse x, if you
UTreduced x，如果你
want to go in the opposite
想去相反的
direction, the equation for
方向，方程
that is, we're going
变为，
to write x approx equals
x approx 等于
U reduce times z.
U reduce乘以 z
Again, just to check the dimensions,
只是为了检查维度，
here U reduce is
这里U reduce 为
going to be an n by k
N*K
dimensional vector, z is
维向量，Z
going to be a k by 1 dimensional vector.
变成k阶一维向量。
So, we multiply these out and that's going to be n by one.
所以，我们将这些相乘，将是一个N。
So x approx is going
所以x approx
to be an n dimensional vector.
是一个N维向量。
And so the intent of PCA,
这就是PCA的意图，
that is, the square projection error
方块上的投影误差
is not too big, is that
不太大，
this x approx will be
x approx将会
close to whatever was
接近
the original value of x
x的初始值
that you had used to derive z in the first place.
你有用于导出Z放在第一位。
To show a picture of what this looks like, this is what it looks like.
这张图片，看起来就是它的样子。
What you get back of this
当你回到
procedure are points that lie
程序点
on the projection of that onto the green line.
的投影到绿色线。
So to take our early example,
所以采取我们早期的样本，
if we started off with
如果我们开始
this value of x1, and got
这个值x1，并得到了
this z1, if you plug
Z1，如果你用
z1 through this formula to get
Z1通过这个公式得到
x1 approx, then this
x1 approx，那么这个
point here, that will be
点在这里，那将是
x1 approx, which is
x1 approx，这
going to be r2 and so.
将变为R2等。
And similarly, if you
同样地，如果你
do the same procedure, this will
做同样的程序，这将
be x2 approx.
是x2 approx。
And you know, that's a pretty
如你所知，这是一个漂亮的
decent approximation to the original data.
与原始数据相当相似。
So, that's how you
所以，这就是你
go back from your low dimensional
从低维
representation z back to
表示Z回到
an uncompressed representation of
未压缩的表示
the data we get back an
我们得到的数据的一个
the approxiamation to your original
之间你的原始
data x, and we
数据X，我们
also call this process reconstruction
也把这个过程称为重建
of the original data.
原始数据。
When we think of trying to reconstruct
当我们认为试图重建
the original value of x from the compressed representation.
从压缩表示x的初始值。
So, given an unlabeled data
所以，给定未标记的数据
set, you now know how to
集，您现在知道如何
apply PCA and take
应用PCA和带
your high dimensional features x and
你的高维特征X和
map it to this
映射到这
lower dimensional representation z, and
的低维表示Z，和
from this video, hopefully you now
这个视频，希望你现在
also know how to take
也知道如何采取
these low representation z and
这些低维表示Z
map the backup to an approximation
映射到备份到一个近似
of your original high dimensional data.
你原有的高维数据。
Now that you know how to
现在你知道如何
implement in applying PCA, what
实施应用PCA，
we will like to do next is to
我们将要做的事是
talk about some of the
谈论
mechanics of how to
一些技术在
actually use PCA well,
实际使用PCA很好，
and in particular, in the next
特别是，在接下来的
video, I like to talk
视频中，我想谈一谈
about how to choose K, which is,
关于如何选择K，这是，
how to choose the dimension
如何选择维度
of this reduced representation vector z.
这减少表示的向量Z。